Background noise

Day 01002: Sunday, 2017 December 03

General news

I don't have much to say today, but I guess I have a couple small notes.

First, I had some bitchy thoughts come back today, but they were so thin and weak ... It's like, they popped into my head, but they had no oomph. I thought them, but I didn't really feel them.

Second, and I've actually been meaning to say this for quite some time, I'm becoming increasingly convinced that the bisexual at work is a bit like me: a mix of man and woman. Gays are weird; I've read this a few places online, though no cause for it was stated or even theorised. My guess though is that it has to do with our mixed masculine/feminine brains. There're probably some quirks caused by having a mixed gender that result in having qualities not found in either gender alone. As we with mixed gender are the oddity, what we are is considered weird. She's quirky like me though. I enjoy her company above that of most of my other coworkers because of that, and I always have. She admits to having man-shaped feet. As a child, she wanted to be male. And her mother thought she would be a lesbian due to her tomboyish personality. She's tough, too. She's far from being a man; she doesn't act like a man, nor does she present herself like one. She's not quite one of the girls though either. It's like ... she's feminine, but a toned-down sort of feminine. If gayness is caused by having a mixed brain (and science suggests that it is), I think bisexuality is caused by a similar sort of mix. I imagine the difference comes from how much of a mix you have, or more precisely, which parts of your brain conform the the configuration of which gender.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Toxic shift leader

Day 01004: Tuesday, 2017 December 05

General news

My strength has definitely returned. There are these pans at work that very few people there can lift when they're stacked too high; I'm one of three that can do it. Well, when I'm feeling well and strong, I can do it. Otherwise, I have to break the stack into two (or more) smaller stacks. Today, lifting the full stack wasn't even difficult.

My coworker tried to get me to take hours off the end of their shift again today. This time, I refused. It was different though. I'm behind in my studies for the week. I have a legitimate reason why I couldn't stay there longer than I had to. Usually, if I don't want to take the hours, it's just because I'm tired or not feeling well. Later, I realised that it was important that I turn down the hours anyway due to the toxic air in the place. They got someone else to cover the hours they wanted dropped, but I still feel bad for the people stuck working.

I talked about liking my bisexual coworker yesterday, but I've changed my mind. They're fun to be around, but they don't care about the safety of the crew. For a couple days, the ventilation fans above our oven have been broken. The noxious gasses spewed by the oven have been just spilling into the room with us. Technically, we should probably close down until they're fixed, but I understand why we don't do that. Besides, I need the hours; I need the pay cheque. Yesterday, when the head manager was in, we kept the front doors and the back door open to create an airflow right past the oven. That worked reasonably well, and I didn't notice any harmful effects from the gasses. Today though, the head manager had the day off.

I came into work feeling very well; I was happy, I was enthusiastic, and and I was energetic. However, after a while, my mood started to sour, and a light headache developed. One of my coworkers went up front to prop open the door, and the shift leader said not to do that. The coworker explained about the broken ventilation, so they were allowed to prop open the door after all. At this point, I realised why I wasn't feeling well, and as the airflow swept away the toxic gas, my headache cleared and I started regaining my pep. A bit later though, the shift leader closed the doors on us. I started regaining my headache and mopey mood. I went and opened them again, both the front doors and back door, my condition improved somewhat, then I started feeling like garbage again. They'd closed the doors again! They knew about the toxic air by wouldn't let us keep the place safe to work in! At one point, the coworker who originally opened the doors told the shift leader I'd been the one to do it this time, not them, even though we both wanted clean air and even though the shift leader hadn't even asked and hadn't even blamed anyone (or even yet noticed the door was open again). Thanks. Just throw me to the wolf for no good reason.

At one point, they got on my case about opening the doors. I explained again the situation with the noxious gasses, but that wasn't enough. I had to *justify* not wanting to breathe *poison*! I went on to explain that I already had a headache from the toxicity. That got them to let me leave the doors open for a little bit, but soon, they were closed once more. They found I again opened the doors, and they said (their words, not mine) they'd "beat my ass" for it. (They were joking, of course, but it's not funny to joke when you're intentionally poisoning your coworkers.) I went into a short spiel about how I know we don't matter and that we're only minimum wage workers, but even *we* deserve clean air. Their response was that city air isn't clean and that if we want clean air, we should live in tents in the woods. Again, a joke, but seriously!? You're poisoning up and making us feel unwell, and you want to claim you don't see a difference between the toxicity level of the outside air and the toxicity level of the garbage spewing from the oven for which we specifically (normally) have ventilation fans to protect us from!? I wasn't the only one feeling the effects either. The other shift leader on duty said the gas was burning their eyes. The coworker that originally opened the doors was likewise concerned about the toxins, though I didn't hear of any specific short-term effect on them. It doesn't matter though; who knows what the long-term effects are?

After a bit, they admitted that we all deserve clean air. However, as I was clocking out, I found they'd closed the doors again; some people still had about two hours left before they could leave. Clearly, they don't actually care about our health and safety. They're as bad as the assistant manager, who was turning off the ventilation system (which was working at the time) simply because they were a little chilly. I imagine the shift leader today had similar motives.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Concern

Day 01009: Sunday, 2017 December 10

General news

I think I'm ready for the next tooth extraction. Mentally, anyway. My body could still use more time to recover.

I was running behind as I headed off to work today, so I didn't have time to grab my jacket. As I left work tonight, my toxic shift leader thought they'd lend me one. Ha! They don't care if they cause me and the rest of the on-duty workers brain damage by locking the noxious oven gasses in the building with us but they care about a little cold!? Yeah ... No. I will continue to treat them in a civil and friendly manner, but we certainly aren't friends. Friends don't poison friends, especially when the friends they're poisoning have expressed concern about it. I refused to borrow the jacket.

At first, I thought this apparent concern ... incongruent with what they'd showed me recently. It was clearly a show. They could look nice by lending me a jacket, but as they admitted, it wasn't one they use, so they weren't giving anything up. They don't actually care. As I typed up that last paragraph though, it hit me: this is *completely* congruent with what they displayed the other day. They smoke; clearly, they don't care as much as some do about breathing toxins. They were locking the noxious fumes in the building with us likely to lock the heat in as well. Their regard for the rest of us is clearly shallow; although at least two of us were expressing immediate health effects and a third was expressing concern, they didn't care. However, they see the cold as an actual threat. They were projecting their threat model on the rest of us and forcing us all to be exposed to what could cause permanent health issues, but their concern tonight was likely genuine. I don't think they were highly concerned or anything, but they weren't faking it. I'm sticking to my "friends don't poison friends" position though. Until a time in which they understand the problem and I think they actually have changed, we're workmates and nothing more.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Eviction

Day 01013: Thursday, 2017 December 14

General news

Apparently, I've been evicted from Opal's machine. I was planning to leave anyway, so this isn't a big deal, but it does show how immature Opal is being. It's funny how I predicted this sort of thing might happen. I didn't think so soon, but this is exactly why I was planning to go somewhere more stable. Anyway, I'm now on GitHub. It's not the best place to be, but it was an easy way to remove myself from Opal's machine quickly. The TLS certificate issue is not moot. I can't use a custom TLS certificate with GitHub's hosting, so I'm stuck using GitHub's certificate. That means three things. First, the certificate is provided by a "trusted" certificate "authority". Second, the certificate still isn't trusted, as the name on the cert and doesn't match the name in the URIs. Third, the certificate error will persist until I have time to move off of GitHub.

If Opal remembers at some point that I'm on Volatile Git, she'll likely delete my repositories there as well. Thankfully, those repositories are a backup of my main repositories at NotABug. If either set is deleted, it's fine, as long as the other set remains intact. I'll continue using Volatile Git and NotABug in parallel until such a point as Opal either expresses a problem with this or outright takes action against it.

I was freaking out a bit yesterday. My gums didn't seem to show any sign of healing yet, and soon, the other side on my mouth will have a gaping hole in it too. How am I supposed to chew!? As I was trying to get to sleep, I realised I should look up the expected time frame for gum-healing after tooth extraction, but I'd already put my computer to sleep. I figured if I let myself wake it back up, there'd be no end to how many times I woke it back up as my mind continued to race. I forced myself to go to sleep, planning to look it up in the morning. It turns out gums usually heal over in about a month. So I'll've gone two weeks between surgeries, which means I'll have a two-week timespan with holes on both sides. My gums seem much better today though. Either there was some sudden healing, which is incredibly unlikely, or just knowing the time frame has helped me considerably, as far as my emotional state. I don't think I'll ever be ready for this next extraction, but it won't be as bad as I've been fearing.

University life

I wasn't feeling great yesterday, so I didn't get much done. I'm going to pay dearly for that this week. Today, the first day of the school week, was spent catching up from last week. Wednesday, the final day of the week, will involve more oral surgery. These will be my only two days off from work for the week. Furthermore, I need to be ahead for next week if I'm to not fall behind when I go visit relatives with my mother.

I plan to dedicate tomorrow and the next day to reading the CS 1104 material and completing any work that needs to be directly completed while reading. The next two or three days, I'll dedicate to the CS 2401 readings and associated coursework. If I'm able to complete that in two days instead of three, I can hopefully get most of my remaining work done on that fifth and final work day. If not, I'll have a bunch to do while trying to get through the pain of tooth extraction.

I was planning to decline the after-surgery pain medication this time ... but I might not do that due to time constraints. Last time, once the pain came, I was pretty much out of commission, mentally. I could complete my mindless work at the company I work for with little difficulty, as I was barely impaired physically, but I couldn't focus on coursework. (I didn't even notice any physical impairment, but I wasn't allowed to lift heavy loads.) I might need the several hours the pain medication can buy me. It's only the one dose though. Unless the pain's much more severe than last time, which I don't anticipate, I won't be taking anything after I leave the dentists' office.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Another surgery

Day 01019: Wednesday, 2017 December 20

General news

I was worried the dentist would want to reschedule the extraction due to the swelling from yesterday's breakfast mishap. The dentist just saw it as a sign the teeth really needed to go though, so we proceeded on schedule. After the procedure, they said they appreciated that I'd come in; they thought I was going to reschedule and put this off. I'm fearful, but I'm no coward. They're the one that wanted to put operating on this side of my mouth off last time, not me. I forgot to mention the bleeding to the dentist though. Oh well, too late now.

I noticed some tabs on their record folder for me this time: three big letter tabs spelling out the name "YST". That got me curious. With the size of the letter tabs, they wouldn't be able to spell most people's surnames, which have about ten or so letters. I asked the dental assistant what they do with people with normal-length names, but got no real response. The dental assistant this time didn't seem to pay much attention, as I'd find out later when they would give me instructions that contradicted what the dentist and I discussed.

Apparently, the swelling and pain in that side of my jaw was due to an abscess. They were able to drain it before pulling any teeth. Most of what I felt this time was pressure, not pain, unlike last time. There was still some pain, but much less. Asking about it, I learned I had an abscess on the other side when they were operating as well, but because it was deeper, they weren't able to drain it beforehand; this was likely the cause of the increased level of pain. With the greatly-reduced pain, I cried a little again, but this time out of relief instead of fear.

The roots on one of my teeth wouldn't come out. The dentist could keep trying, but it seems those roots are near a nerve and the dentist doesn't want to push it. I should've asked what the implications of the nearby nerve are, but I wasn't quite in the calm state of mind needed to think of such questions until I got home. They're going to refer me to a specialist to get the roots removed, but the top of the tooth is already gone. They did some cutting with the drill, but this time, they only revved it the first time before putting it in my mouth. Subsequent times, when I thought they were done with the drill as they'd started working with other tools, I'd find myself surprised to hear the drill in my mouth again. They didn't give me any stitches either, likely because the specialist is going to need to get in there.

I distracted myself most of the time with random thoughts to try to keep calm. At first, I thought about their tools. I'm unsure of the nature of these tools, but they're colour-coded; red and yellow. Because of the colours, one of the other dentists named them "ketchup" and "mustard". So they have tools named after condiments, and they put them in people's mouths. Hilarious. I was reacting to the stuff going on in my mouth, but a couple "reactions" the dentist must have seen were actually short, stifled giggles. Later, the dentist asked their assistant for the precepts. I immediately thought of an arm with bulging biceps and a hot torso with rippling abs attached to it. Soon after, I started thinking about how the dentist had their hands in the mouth of a queer and probably had no idea.

I may not have been in the right mind to ask about the implications of the nearby nerve, but I did remember to ask a couple questions I had since last time. When the other assistant had told me a denture would prevent bone loss, I'd meant to ask the dentist about it during that same visit. I asked this time, and they said it would *slow* the bone loss, not prevent it. I also planned to ask the dentist about syringes as well. My post-op care instructions told me to rinse out the hole in my gums with a syringe, but where was I supposed to get one of those? I forgot to ask the dentist, but I remembered in time to ask the dental assistant as they were checking me out. They gave me one from the office's supply room.

The dental assistant threw out the teeth this time, so we don't get a bloody picture this time. I've also been asked to start taking the antibiotics that I was prescribed last time. Before, they were just in case of fever, but this time, I'm to take them regardless. The dentist didn't give me any pain medication before I left this time though, and the pain started setting in as I biked home. Worse than the pain in my jaw was that in my brain; I had a bad headache after the procedure. I'll make it through though. I have the pain medication prescribed last time here at home, but I'm not going to take it unless I get desperate.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

University life

After taking the time to write about my dental experience, I laid down to rest a few minutes. I couldn't let myself rest any longer than that though, as I had an essay to write. Soon, I found myself unable to concentrate, so I rested for a bit more. I couldn't really relax either though, so within minutes, I was back to working on my essay again. I ended up taking a long soak in a warm bathtub to try to feel better. That's the first time I've soaked since Coos Bay, to be honest. We had a hot tub there that I'd sometimes use when no one was around. After that, I sort of alternated between lying down in the bedroom and doing coursework in the kitchen until I gave up and brought my laptop to bed with me. That way, I could work on my essay whenever I had a small bit of strength to work on it instead of just when Id built up enough strength to get out of bed for a while.

My essay came out ... bad. It's not like I really care right now though; I'm not feeling well enough to care. My test cases came out well, mostly because I did the write-up yesterday before the procedure. I didn't finish my learning journal assignments and get them submitted before the school week ended (at 21:00 in my time zone), but I guess it was never my goal to. I did get them finished by midnight in my time zone, which was the real goal. Tomorrow, hopefully I'll feel much better and can begin to tackle the next week's tasks right away. If not, I'll have a rough(er) week ahead of me.

I posted my new course decisions several days ago, but that entry is going to have to be redacted until 2023-01-01. A couple days later, I wrote up an explanation detailing a new format for my course tree. Again, redacted until 2023-01-01. Long story short though, the old format links to the now-redacted coursework index, which is suboptimal, and it also represents my former attitude toward the school. This new format avoids linking to the redacted index by avoiding mentioning past courses. This is a necessary change, as the only way completed and scheduled courses were distinguished from future courses was the fact that if they were completed or scheduled, their names were hyperlinked. It better represents my new attitude, as I no longer feel like I'm accumulating anything. Coursework has become drudgery. I used to like to see how far I've come, but I'm not really getting anywhere. All that's left is the list of what's left to get through.

Anyway, it's helpful for me to have the list of what's left to do on a publicly-accessible journal page. It means I can save a bookmark in my Web browser and return here when it comes time to select the next courses. Reformatting has let me do that. Without further ado, let me say that I'll be taking an algebra course and an English course, both proctored, and present my current left-to-do list:

CS 2204

CS 4404

CS 3303

CS 3304

CS 4407*

CS 4408*

CS 4406*

CS 3308*

All of these: CS 3305*, CS 4405, CS 3307, CS 4403, CS 4402, CS 3306*, MATH 1211, MATH 1280*, MATH 1302
One of these: BIOL 1121, BIOL 1301, ENVS 1301
One of these: ECON 1580, PSYC 1111, PSYC 1205, PSYC 1504, SOC 1502
One (two) of these: AHIST 1401, ENGL 1405, PHIL 1402
One (four) electives

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

ALEX

Day 01023: Sunday, 2017 December 24

General news

Our mother's quite frustrated. Some things aren't going as she planned, though her plans were, quite honestly, unrealistic. For starters, she she wants nothing to do with her only son, Cyrus. Due to the court-ordered visitation schedule, Vanessa has to go to our father's place tomorrow. My mother's plan was for Cyrus to stay out of visibility while we were here, then travel with Vanessa and our father to our father's place. Um. What? Anyway, Cyrus instead has already made the trip to our fathers place, which is the only realistic option, given how our mother is acting. Vivian also assumed the holiday would end fairly early in the morning tomorrow for our mother, as Vanessa would have to leave. So Vivian made plans for later in the day. Apparently, our mother's planning to hold Vanessa longer than legally allowed though, and has conned Vanessa into playing along. That has two implications. First, our mother was able to make plans for further in the day than Vivian had anticipated. Second, our mother's plan for our brother was to wait even longer, potentially spending the entire holiday alone. Our mother is so inconsiderate at times.

That said, our mother can be very thoughtful as well. I think she's trying to be understanding of my new understanding of myself, though she sees it in pieces. Today, she gave me a thoughtful gift, a framed set of four photographs of moss. She's arranged the moss to spell out the name "ALEX". (I snapped a photograph of it to post in this journal entry, but with my mobile refusing to speak with my laptop, I wasn't able to actually include it.) It's definitely a more thoughtful gift than I thought her capable of, and a nicer gift than I could imagine receiving from anyone. It made me feel bad about the simple plush dragon I bought her. This month has taken a lot out of me though, so I wasn't able to put much into it; not to mention that she's always been terrible at choosing gifts for me because she tends to block out that which she doesn't like. I'll need to make sure to put more into her gift for next year, but I'm also doing better and should have more time. I already have a good idea as to what to make her as well. She also bought Vivian and I each a set of borosilicate storage containers with lids. I think the lids are plastic, but being borosilicate, the bottoms can be cooked in.

A couple of our other relatives also gave us gifts, which is incredibly odd. Our branch of the family has never been included in the main family gift exchange, so we didn't know to bring anything.

University life

I'm cut off. My mobile is refusing to speak with my laptop now, so I can't reach the Internet. I tried replacing the cord, but that didn't work; the cord isn't what's broken. Joy. I won't be able to work on the discussion assignments during the trip, nor will I be able to do any research if I need to.

Our mother only got an hour of sleep, so she postponed the trip by several hours. She was able to get another hour of sleep, but that was all. As horrible as it was that she didn't feel well, it did buy me time to get a lot of coursework done.

Document modifications

On 2018-01-16, my sister, Vivian, requested that I replace all instances of her legal name in my journal with the name "Vivian". She also asked that the name of the organisation she works for be redacted. This page was modified to fulfil that request.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

I don't think I can go through that again.

Day 01025: Tuesday, 2017 December 26

Discussion of implants

Late last night, as I was going to bed, my mother insisted on seeing the holes in my gums. I don't see the thrill myself, but whatever. But then she started apologising that I hadn't had insurance for so long; as if it was her fault we could never afford insurance and as if insurance would have done anything besides postpone the inevitable. The only thing she's to blame for though is creating me. She has bad DNA and should never have used it to create offspring; I will not make that same mistake. Then she mentioned the hope that I'd one day have better insurance that would cover implants. I've been asking questions of the dentist; I've been trying to get the information in case I change my mind. However, since realising just how much I need to recover from after the surgery ... Since realising that they're ripping holes to and into my *bone* ... I haven't been big on the idea of more oral surgery. I don't think I want implants. I don't think I like the idea of things jutting out of my bone and to the surface. Real teeth are bad enough, if not worse. Not only do they require a hole to the surface to pass through, they also rot ant act as a vessel for infection to reach and take hold in my jawbone. The idea of an implant isn't a good one though. While not as bad as a real tooth, they're still tunnelling through my fleshy, self-healing surface layer.

One thing sticks out as the most traumatic experience I've ever had, both because of the duration and because of the profoundly negative effect on my mind. It took months to recover. The second-most traumatic experience I've ever had though, I think, has been this experience with the dentist. I was fine until the night before the first surgery. The short-term implications of it dawned on me then though. I didn't get much sleep. During that first surgery, the pain and the horror really got to me. I think I was partly in shock, too. Then ... the dentist didn't even finish the job. They left part of it for a couple weeks later. They told me I could have this over with in one sitting, but took that hope away from me. I'd have to come back and experience all this again. The dentist mentioned wanting to make me too loopy to bike home for the next surgery, as well. They wanted to find me a ride, but I refused. I couldn't let my dental appointment commute unnecessarily burn fossil fuels. No one seems to care, and what I do makes so little difference compared to the combined damage everyone else causes ... But I can't add to the problem. Too much damage is being done to the planet already. Even if I could afford to be loopy, I couldn't take the ride, so the dentist decided it wasn't safe to dope me up next time. I had coursework to do though. The dentist was worried about safety, but I'd've had to turn down the loopy drugs myself if they hadn't decided not to use them on me.

So here I was, having just gone through surgery that did quite a number on me emotionally, and the dentist now wanted the next surgery to involve heavier drugs. My only expectation that the dentist thought this surgery would be worse, but because I couldn't afford to take the drugs they wanted me to, it'd be even worse than worse. I spent the nearly-two weeks between appointments dreading the next appointment. When it dawned on me soon after the first surgery how much I needed to recover, my horror grew. I would not have had the strength to go back in if not for the fact that I knew things would only get worse. I knew since before I met the dentist that these teeth would have to go and that there was no other option. During the first surgery, it got so bad the dentist had to stop and give me a short break. During that time, I was able to steel my nerves, so the rest of the surgery went better emotionally. During the second surgery, I was able to keep my strength the until it ended. Once I was out the door though ... I think I went into a mild shock. If not for the near-immediate onset of the pain, I'd've likely done worse; the pain distracted me well though.

I don't think I can go through that again. Not before I have to. One by one, the rest of my teeth will rot. This is inevitable. It's one of a multitude of reasons I refuse to create more people out of my own DNA. I can't knowingly inflict this on anyone, especially someone that hasn't even done *anything* to deserve it. Even as a small child, I've always strongly believed that those with poor genetics, such as myself, have a responsibility not to pass their bad genes on. When the inevitable happens, my newly-rotten teeth will need to be extracted and I'll need to repeat this process. But I don't think I'm up for anything extra. I can withstand the pain, but I don't think I can withstand the horror, at least for the time being. My mother doesn't seem to accept this though. She's mad that I don't want implants. It's not her body, it's not her experiencing this, and it's not her decision. She has no right to be angry with a decision that doesn't even affect her. Her lack of understanding though is painful. I can't help but wonder if she'd act any differently if she realised I cried myself to sleep last night. The fact that she'd think it's okay to unnecessarily impose such trauma on me again ... That she'd think her opinions on other people's medical decisions should trump their own ... I have to admit this is much more in character for her though than I've seen her acting lately. I'd hoped she'd changed, but it's clear she hasn't. She still considers anyone with a differing opinion than her, even about matters that don't concern her, to be unquestionably and objectively wrong. To her, only her own opinion can ever truly be correct, because only her own thoughts and opinions matter.

Journal sections

A while back, I got fed up with the wall of text my journal entries had become. I set up a set of categories to split my writing into. As life situations changed, so did my pre-defined categories, but there was always a set of categories at hand with which to group things into. I realised early this morning that this format's inflexible though. I often group logically-separate blurbs together because they fit into the same vague category or they don't fit into any category, and belong in the fallback category. For example, this paragraph on the formatting of my journal has nothing to do with the preceding paragraphs I wrote to work through the pain I was feeling last night, but they'd've both ended up in the #general section. That's kind of ugly. I'm now deleting all the predefined categories, and going free-form. I'll section things based on however they need to be sectioned for the day; the results should be a lot better. I'm not sure how to properly convey the ids of the sections in a nonintrusive way though. That'll have to come later. Another benefit of this new setup is that the sections can be in a more chronological order. Previously, there was a specific order to the sections, but now, I can put them in the order in which they occur. For example, this section comes before the #dream section today, which means it was likely at least mostly written before I went to sleep.

While I'm on the topic, I eventually need to clean up the markup on my old pages. I used to put ids in heading tags, but especially with the new CSS adjustments I've made since then, they really belong in the <section/> tags.

Dream journal

I dreamed I was planning to go to a party with my coworkers. I put on a white, crochet dress with a fabric underlining that prevented gaps in the crochet layer from showing skin. It zipped up the front, didn't show my chest, and was knee-length. It was beautiful, but a bit thick. I debated back and fourth about whether I was ready for my cowerkers to see me in clothing that was so obviously feminine though. I mean, I've worn women's shits to work before, but not dresses. I openly identify as nonbinary, but most people still think I'm a man.

Tardiness

I knew it. I just knew it. My mother has always been one to push deadlines. As a child, she'd always take me to my orchestra concerts (that I was *playing* in) late. Last night, she decided to hold me out of town for another overnight, asking when I had work this morning. That wasn't what we agreed to. I told her I needed to work an hour before I did though, and told her I needed an hour to get ready and for commute time. That should've given me the two hours I needed to settle in, get ready, and make it on time. I knew I'd only get the one hour though. She dropped me off late, as expected. I barely had time to unwind a little, I didn't have time to get lunch before work, and I didn't have time to prepare dinner to eat at work. It doesn't help that I haven't eaten much in days, being that I haven't been home and have been unable to control the menu. I'm lucky that my cousin, whom with we've been staying, was accommodating in meal preparation. Still though, I dont' do well when I can't continually eat. Being an herbavore, I don't get enough energy from simple, all-at-once meals. Had I told her my honest work time, I'd've been late to work if I hadn't grabbed my work clothes and headed out the door in a mad rush. Another hour. Each time she cuts it this close, I'm adding another hour of cushion time without her knowledge. I'll find the proper amount of cushion time I need to deal with my mother's inability to meet deadlines.

My mother seemed to think she could buy some time by dropping me off at work, too. Um. No. I was going to use my bike as an excuse, saying I'd need to bike to work so I'd have my bike to ride it home. It was only an excuse, but she actually reached that conclusion without any hinting from me. She saw dropping me off directly at work wouldn't work out on her own, so I didn't need to say a word except in agreement with her. Which helps, seeing as she doesn't take well to people opposing her for any reason, as I discussed before I was able to get to bed this morning.

University coursework

I was planning to finish my final unquarantined discussion post for the week today, but as I was starting it, we finally left to go home. I would've finished it once we got home, but we got home way behind schedule and there was no time before work. I tried to fit it in after work, but the Internet connection was agonizingly slow; I wasn't able to get to the discussion forum before midnight.

I might've gotten to the discussion before midnight, but I needed to deal with other matters on this agonising-slow connection. For example, it seems the school's now pulling garbage claiming I haven't set a proctor for one of my two upcoming courses, even though I set one for each. They changed the interface on me, and the new one's incredibly bugged up. It shows that I've registered both proctors, but only allows the option to resent the email to one of them.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Surgeon

Day 01026: Wednesday, 2017 December 27

My exam proctor, the University of Oregon testing centre, says they accepted the proctor position via the links in both emails, one for each course, on the twentieth. They even know the names of the courses without my telling them, meaning that there's zero chance the school didn't properly process the information I gave them. I swear, my school in so mixed up a lot of the time. However, they asked if they should confirm again, so I said to try it while I was waiting for a response from my program advisor about the matter, and I've now received the confirmation-of-confirmation emails. Either the testing centre lied to me today and hadn't touched the acceptance links or (more likely) my university's system is messing up.

My discussion post for the day:

I think you were the only student this week to recognise both types of interrupts. Great job! Each of them play a vital, though differing, role. Some interrupts are for dealing with the input devices, while other interrupts are for multitasking with the CPU.

Dental work

As expected, the dental office didn't contact me about the specialist as they were supposed to. I've been out of town and unable to do anything about that, but today, I reached out to them to see what the deal was. What I didn't expect was that they'd redirect my message to someone that'd try to use a broken "secure email" system to speak with me. First of all, it wasn't even email, but a Web-based messaging system. I wish people would stop trying to pass that off as any sort of email. I don't care if you want to reach me via a Web-based chat system, just don't call it "secure email"; it isn't. Anyway, to use their system, it was required that I set up an account. The system refused to allow my password, but also didn't tell me what it didn't like about my password so I could fix it. I tried several passwords, the system declined them all. I wrote back to figure out what the password requirements were, but can you guess what happened? I received another real email alerting me to the fact that I'd received another "secure email". They were replying and trying to help me get onto the system via the system I couldn't get onto without help. How in Squiddy's name did they expect me to read their messages!? I swear, someone on staff must be a complete moron. Anyway, I was able to get in touch with my original contact, who this time got the second person to use real email. That's not what I was after (I was only trying to get the password requirements to set up my account on their system they wanted me to use), but it works for me. Real email's so much easier to work with.

Anyway, I've got the address of the office the specialist works in, and they're said to be an oral surgeon. I'm curious as to what the difference between an oral surgeon and a dentist is, seeing as the dentist performed oral surgery on me. Twice. Maybe the surgeon doesn't also do drilling and such; I'm not sure if cavity-drilling and -filling count as surgery. I'll probably try to get into the surgeon's office tomorrow to set up an appointment. It's a bit far and I can't copy a map from my laptop to my mobile any more, so this could prove to be a challenge.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Hack assembler

Day 01028: Friday, 2017 December 29

include.d version 0.0.1.7

Ugh. I don't feel well today. My faeces have been becoming increasingly liquidy, until today, I swear they were mostly water. And now I have a stomachache, can't keep hydrated, and am having difficulties focussing on my studies. I don't have time for this. Like last time, my dental appointment lands on my day off, the final day of the school week. I also spent much of yesterday, my other day off for the week, trying to find my way to the dentists' office to even make the appointment. I need to keep on task. The workload this week is lower than normal, at least theoretically, but I'm required to use an assembler that I was never able to get running. The professor has offered no help whatsoever, despite my several mentions to them that I couldn't get it working. That said, I didn't actually *ask* for help, so I can't complain too much, but I don't really feel like asking for help from someone that represents a school that doesn't seem to care.

Anyway, to replace the assembler I have to use, I've built my own assembler. It certainly enhanced my understanding of assemblers, but it also took a lot of time that I feel I don't have. Well, sort of don't have. As long as I keep focussed, this shouldn't be a problem.

As a side note, it's interesting to me that the school's censorship rules can be applied in either direction. For example, I've already posted my assembler publicly. This is a fact. However, we were never required to build it, assuming we got the supplied assembler working. That means that as long as I don't include my assembler in anything I submit to the school, I haven't broken any rules. However, if I *do* include it in my learning journal or in the discussion forum, even though my public posting of it will have come first, I'll be in violation of the rules. That means that to avoid trouble, I have to censor *what I'm going to submit to the school*. I imagine that's not at all how they intended their rule, but it certainly will keep me out of trouble.

Anyway, as I said, I've posted my assembler publicly. The bulk of the work is done by a pair of new classes in my new include.d release, version 0.0.1.7. The rest of the work is done by this short script here:

<?php declare(strict_types=1);
/**
 * Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst <mailto:copyright@y.st>
 * 
 * This program is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify
 * it under the terms of the GNU General Public License as published by
 * the Free Software Foundation, either version 3 of the License, or
 * (at your option) any later version.
 * 
 * This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
 * but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
 * MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE. See the
 * GNU General Public License for more details.
 * 
 * You should have received a copy of the GNU General Public License
 * along with this program. If not, see <http://www.gnu.org./licenses/>.
**/

// Causes all errors to be terminal
require 'st/y/function/error_handler.php';
set_error_handler('\\st\\y\\error_handler');
// Sets the script up to used the classes from include.d
spl_autoload_register();

$input = file_get_contents($argv[1]);

$symbol = new \st\y\hack\symbol_table();
$lines = explode("\n", $input);
$address = 0;

foreach($lines as $l => &$line):
	$comment = strpos($line, '//');
	if($comment !== false):
		$line = substr($line, 0, $comment);
	endif;
	$line = preg_replace('{\\s}', '', $line);
	$length = strlen($line);
	if($line == ''):
		unset($lines[$l]);
	elseif($line[0] == '(' and $line[$length-1] == ')'):
		$symbol[substr($line, 1, -1)] = $address;
		unset($lines[$l]);
	else:
		$address++;
	endif;
endforeach;
unset($line);

foreach($lines as $line):
	echo new \st\y\hack\instruction($line, $symbol), "\n";
endforeach;

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Difficulties

Day 01029: Saturday, 2017 December 30

University drudgery

I worked on my coursework some, but I'm having a bit of an issue grasping the topic at hand. After a while, I gave up ant took a break, which ended up lasting longer than intended. I got distracted looking at various Debian VPSes available. I had a shift today too that both began early and ended late. That further cut into my coursework time.

Food for thought

I don't want to say anything about specific people, just because it'd make them look bad and that's not the goal here. However, I was presented with a couple new thoughts by the person I was working with today. First, they brought to the surface the realisation that I shouldn't be going out of my way to spare the feelings of toxic people. (If you've been reading my journal, you probably know who I mean.) I don't think that idea was their intent, but they did agree with it. Still, I'm mild mannered and wouldn't hurt someone intentionally whether I like them or not, but I shouldn't put the extra care and effort into making sure not to hurt those that don't mind hurting me.

Second, we have a bit of a braggart on the payroll. They complete tasks quickly, time it, then tell the rest of us about it. I was never super impressed, but I was mildly impressed. They cut the braggart down to size real quickly though. All they did was ask about the quality of the speedy work. I hadn't considered that. The main thing the braggart is terrible at is cleaning; that's also what they most like to brag about. I'm no longer impressed whatsoever. Anyway, the moral of the story is that if you've got a braggart on your hands, and you're actually impressed in any way, try thinking about what they've sacrificed in exchange for the impressive feat. Sure, you can clean things quickly if you don't actually get them clean, but is that actually impressive?

Today ends my prescribed amoxicillin doses. I don't think I've had the stuff before, but my mother's allergic to it, as is Vivian. Also, my mother's reaction to it doesn't begin until about ten days after she quits taking it; then she breaks out in hives. So ... yeah ... In about ten days, I get to see if I have the same reaction to it as my mother. If I do, this isn't going to be pleasant. With my poor luck streak still completely intact (I thought it'd ended, but then there was the garbage with the school to keep the chain going), I probably am allergic to it, but like my mother, not in any lethal way. My luck's been bad, but not bad enough to be anywhere near fatal.

Document modifications

On 2018-01-16, my sister, Vivian, requested that I replace all instances of her legal name in my journal with the name "Vivian". She also asked that the name of the organisation she works for be redacted. This page was modified to fulfil that request.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.